Finding Aid for the Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2005
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2005
Mus. Arc. 27
Haupt, Irene
1 box (47 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 47 photographs of musicians who participated in the June in Buffalo Festival 2005 at the University at Buffalo
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Irene Haupt, 2005.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
All images are available in the UB Libraries Digital Collections as part of the overall June in Buffalo Collection.
Biographical Note
Irene Haupt, a graduate of the State University of New York at Buffalo, has been documenting the Buffalo arts scene through her photography since 1976. During that time she has worked for, or with, some of the most notable institutions in Buffalo, including the Irish Classical Theatre, Studio Arena Theater, the Kavinoky Theatre, the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, the Theatre of Youth, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. In addition to her specialty of theater photography, Irene Haupt has also devoted much of her career to the photography of musicians and musical events. Most notable is her documentation of the contemporary music scene in Buffalo, including coverage of the University at Buffalo's June in Buffalo festival of new music, 1982-1987, and 2005 to the present. Over the course of those years, she has created a visual record that contains images of some of the most significant composers and performers of the last quarter century. The list of names is impressive: Aaron Copland, Morton Feldman, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, Steve Reich, Ralph Shapey, Henry Brant, Earle Brown, Ursula Oppens, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Otto Luening, Conlon Nancarrow, Ernst Krenek, Larry Austin, Lejaren Hiller, Elliott Carter, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Charles Wuorinen, Jacob Druckman, and Yvar Mikhashoff, among others.
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was begun at the University at Buffalo in 1975 by composer Morton Feldman. He directed the festival 1975-1978 and in 1980. The festival was dormant from 1981 through 1985. David Felder revived the festival in 1986 and has been its director since that time.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005 contains 47 images of participants in the festival for 2005. The list of musicians includes David Felder, Simon Bainbridge, Philippe Manoury, Brian Ferneyhough, Tony Arnold, Christopher Rouse, James Avery, Alvin Lucier, Magnus Martensson, Jonathan Golove, and Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman.
Arrangement
One sequence of images in alphabetical order by principal subject of the image.
Container List
- Photographs, June 2005, I.
  - Tony Arnold on stage at Slee Concert Hall, June 2005, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 01)
  - Tony Arnold on stage at Slee Concert Hall, June 2005, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 02)
  - Tony Arnold on stage at Slee Concert Hall, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 03)
  - Tony Arnold with Jacob Greenberg at the piano, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 04)
  - Tony Arnold, with Jacob Greenberg and Simon Bainbridge, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 05)
  - James Avery, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 06)
  - Simon Bainbridge, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 07)
  - Simon Bainbridge, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 08)
  - Simon Bainbridge in lobby of Baird Hall, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 09)
  - Simon Bainbridge, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10)
  - Simon Bainbridge in walkway between Slee and Baird Halls, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Simon Bainbridge, Alvin Lucier, and Christopher Rouse, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 12)
  - J. T. Rinker, Simon Bainbridge, and David Felder, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13)
  - David Felder and unidentified male, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14)
  - David Felder, Brian Ferneyhough, and Simon Bainbridge in lobby of Slee Hall, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and Jayn Rosenfeld (partially hidden), June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and David Felder, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and David Felder, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and David Felder, June 2005, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and David Felder, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and David Felder, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and David Felder, with Jayn Rosenfeld in background, June 2005, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman and David Felder, with Jayn Rosenfeld in background, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24)
  - Trond Saeverud, Jacob Greenberg, and Jonathan Golove, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25)
  - Sven Thomas Kiebler, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Alvin Lucier, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Alvin Lucier, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28)
  - Alvin Lucier, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29)
  - Alvin Lucier, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 30)
  - Philippe Manoury, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 31)
  - Philippe Manoury examining score, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32)
  - Philippe Manoury, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 33)
  - Magnus Mårtensson conducting chamber ensemble, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 34)
  - Magnus Mårtensson conducting chamber ensemble, June 2005, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Ian Pace at the piano, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 36)
  - Ian Pace at the piano, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37)
  - Ian Pace at the piano, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38)
  - Ian Pace at the piano, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39)
  - Ian Pace at the piano, June 2005, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 40)
  - Ian Pace at the piano, June 2005, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 41)
  - Ian Pace at the piano, June 2005, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 42)
  - Ian Pace at the piano, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 43)
  - Quatuor Diotima with composer Aaron Cassidy, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 44)
  - J. T. Rinker at sound console, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 45)
  - Christopher Rouse and David Felder, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 46)
  - Christopher Rouse, June 2005, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 47)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
June in Buffalo (Festival) (Buffalo, N.Y.)--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Music festivals--New York(State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs
Genres
Photographs; Portraits
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005
Mus. Arc. 18
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2000 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2001
Mus. Arc. 19
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2001 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2002
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2002 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2003
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2003 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004
Mus. Arc. 25
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2004 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2006 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2007
Mus. Arc. 38
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2007 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2008
Mus. Arc. 39
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2008 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2009
Mus. Arc. 50
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2009 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2010
Mus. Arc. 55
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2010 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2011
Mus. Arc. 56
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2011 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2012
Mus. Arc. 60
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2012 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2013
Mus. Arc. 66
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2013 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2014
Mus. Arc. 67
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2014 June in Buffalo.
June in Buffalo Photograph Collection
A selection of images from the June in Buffalo festivals is available through University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.